# INGENIERO VICTOR LEÓN

## Full-Stack Developer

+584249321489 • vdleon30@gmail.com • https://www.linkedin.com/in/victor-león • Venezuela

### Summary

Full-stack Developer with over 7 years of experience working primarily with Laravel, Angular, and React frameworks, and a strong command of PHP, JavaScript, and Jquery. I have successfully led projects in E-commerce, language learning websites, and custom web/mobile platforms. Additionally, I have experience with Spring Boot, WordPress, and Golang. My goal is to apply my Full-stack development skills and self-taught approach to drive the success of innovative projects, contributing to the growth and efficiency of companies that value technological excellence.

#### Skills

•	Laravel	•	Git	•	PostgreSQL
•	PHP	•	GitLab	•	React
•	Ionic	•	jQuery	•	React Native
•	Angular	•	Unit Testing	•	SQL
•	TypeScript	•	Java	•	API REST
•	JavaScript	•	Linux	•	Apple iOS
Languages					
•	lonic Angular TypeScript	•	jQuery Unit Testing Java Linux	•	React Native SQL API REST

Spanish Native ♥ ● ● ● ● English Intermediate ● ● ■ Portuguese Competent

## Experience

Ciudad de México, México

#### Full-Stack Developer at 789mx

11/2021 - 12/2024

- Development of REST APIs to serve mobile applications (Android and iOS), APP customization based on API data reception and integration.
- Re-engineering for application and website performance optimization.
- Project Manager for 2 projects.
- Head of Development for 5 projects.
- Creation and maintenance of projects from scratch.
- Server control for website deployments and maintenance.
- Technology Stack: Laravel, Laravel Passport, Ionic (Angular), APIs, Jquery, Laravel Blade, Bootstrap, MySql.

Ciudad de Panamá, Panamá

03/2020 - 11/2020

## Back-End Developer at Fortesza

- Creation and maintenance of REST APIs.
- Integration of a US Stock Market Investment Platform (Alpaca).
- Maintenance of administrative modules.
- Management of electronic Wallets with withdrawals, deposits, and asset retention.
- Technology Stack: Laravel, MySql.

Santiago, Chile

Texas, E.E.U.U

04/2019 - 01/2020

#### Front-End Developer at Rolsoft

- Creation of Apps for E-commerce.
- Maintenance of administrative and custom apps.
- Landing Page creation.
- Responsible for 2 administrative projects for a government entity.
- App deployments in stores.
- Directly involved in the development from scratch of 9 apps and websites.
- Technology Stack: Angular, React, Ionic, Jquery, React Native.

#### Full-Stack Developer at LingoCulture

06/2018 - 10/2019

- Creation of modules on landing page with WordPress.
- Maintenance of a platform for learning French from English.
- Re-engineering for performance optimization across the entire project.
- Technology Stack: Laravel, Jquery, JavaScript, MySql, WordPress.

## Experience

Ibagué, Colombia 05/2017 - 06/2018

## Desarrollador Full-Stack en Imagina Colombia

- Creation of landing pages.
- Maintenance of administrative site.
- Development of multiple modules for the website.
- Responsible for all Google connection and configuration for notifications, translation engines, reading and listening exercises in English for the language learning platform.
- Optimization of the live class scheduling process for the learning platform.

#### Education

## Universidad Nacional Experimental de Guayana

**Computer Engineering** 

Puerto Ordaz, Venezuela Title obtained

Universidad De Carabobo

#### Computer, Informatics and Systems Workshop

- Debian GNU/Linux
- Functional Programming in Haskell
- Public Software

Valencia, Venezuela 11/2015 - 11/2015

## Training / Courses

Between B1 Intermediate and B2 Upper Intermediate \_\_ EF Standard English Test (EF NOV, 2023)